<resources>
    <string name="app_name">EinkScrollerTest</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="sample_text_en">Since his first wife vanished more than three decades ago, Robert A. Durst, the eccentric and estranged son of one of New York’s most prominent real estate dynasties, has lived under the suspicious gaze of law enforcement officials in three states.

They have followed his path from New York City to Los Angeles, where one of his closest friends was found dead in her home in 2000. They have tracked him to Galveston, Tex., where he fled after investigators reopened the case of his wife\’s disappearance, and where he posed as a mute woman and shot and dismembered a neighbor in 2001.

Mr. Durst was acquitted in the Texas killing, and was never arrested in the disappearance of his wife or the death of his friend. But on Saturday, he found himself in custody once again, arrested on a charge of murder as he walked into a New Orleans hotel he had checked into under a false name.

On Sunday night, in the final moments of the final episode of a six-part HBO documentary about him, “The Jinx: The Life and Deaths of Robert Durst,” Mr. Durst seemed to veer toward a confession that could lift the shroud of mystery that surrounds the deaths of three people over the course of three decades.

“What the hell did I do?” Mr. Durst whispers to himself in an unguarded moment caught on a microphone he wore during filming. \“Killed them all, of course.\”

In the years since his wife, Kathleen Durst, disappeared in 1982 after spending the weekend at the couple’s country home in Westchester County, Mr. Durst has bounced in and out of jail for other crimes, cut ties with his family, remarried, and sued his brother for a $65 million share of the family fortune. Through it all, he has maintained his innocence in the disappearance of his wife, while also denying any role in the 2000 death of the Los Angeles friend, Susan Berman.

His arrest on Saturday in a Marriott on Canal Street in New Orleans was in connection with Ms. Berman’s death, though the Westchester authorities said they were still investigating him in his wife’s case. Mr. Durst was walking toward an elevator and mumbling to himself when F.B.I. agents intercepted him at the hotel, a law enforcement official briefed on the investigation said. He had checked in under the name Everett Ward, not the first time he had used an alias.

Mr. Durst is believed to have left Houston in a Toyota Camry on March 10, headed for New Orleans. Investigators involved in the case said they feared that the renewed attention brought by “The Jinx” would lead him to try to flee the country. Mr. Durst will plead not guilty, said one of his lawyers, Dick DeGuerin, who helped win Mr. Durst’s acquittal in Galveston in 2003 and who said he expected to head Mr. Durst’s defense team in Los Angeles.

“The rumors that have been flying for years will now get tested in court,” Mr. DeGuerin said.

As he watched the documentary Sunday night with the filmmakers, James McCormack, the brother of Kathleen Durst, said, “Closure is near at hand; I feel in my heart.”

It was Mr. Durst himself who may have set the latest twist in his bizarre saga in motion. Los Angeles prosecutors reopened their investigation into Ms. Berman’s execution-style murder only after Mr. Durst agreed to a series of interviews with the producers of “The Jinx,” Andrew Jarecki and Marc Smerling.

The amount of press coverage Mr. Durst has generated is topped only by the volume of work he has made for his lawyers and police investigators in Westchester, Los Angeles, Galveston and beyond. Yet he had rebuffed overtures from journalists until he saw “All Good Things,” a lightly fictionalized film the producers had previously made of his life in 2010, and approached them to tell his story.

“I will be able to tell it my way,” he said in the second episode of “The Jinx.”

Photo


Kathleen Durst and Mr. Durst in the 1970s, in a photo provided by HBO. Ms. Durst, his first wife, disappeared in 1982. She was declared legally dead. Credit James McCormack
In a more recent interview, he brushed off the possibility that the documentary would whet prosecutors’ appetites, saying: “It’s so long ago. Some D.A. would have to commence a budget-busting investigation. I don’t see that happening.”

By then, a new investigation was already encircling him.

“These two producers did what law enforcement in three states could not do in 30 years,” said Jeanine F. Pirro, the former Westchester County district attorney, whose office investigated Kathleen Durst’s disappearance for six years. “Kudos to them. They were meticulous. They were focused. They were clear.”

The filmmakers spent nearly 10 years researching Mr. Durst’s story: his upbringing as the eldest son of a family that controls 11 major skyscrapers in New York; his marriage to Ms. Durst, a medical student who lived in one of his family’s buildings, and its unraveling; his estrangement from his family after his father chose his younger brother, Douglas Durst, to run the business in 1994.

“We are relieved and also grateful to everyone who assisted in the arrest of Robert Durst,” Douglas Durst said in a statement on Sunday. “We hope he will finally be held accountable for all he has done.”

When prosecutors began pursuing new leads in his wife’s disappearance in 2000, Mr. Durst fled to Galveston, posing as a mute woman to rent a $300-a-month room in the Gulf Coast city. The next year, he was on the run again, with a warrant out for his arrest in the murder of Morris Black, a former merchant seaman who had lived across the hall in Galveston. After a nationwide manhunt, he was found in Bethlehem, Pa., where he had shoplifted a sandwich from a Wegmans supermarket.

Mr. Durst convinced a Texas jury that Mr. Black had died accidentally when the two men were grappling over a gun that discharged as they fell to the floor. He testified that he had carved up Mr. Black’s body until he was “swimming in blood.”

But he was still under suspicion in the death of Ms. Berman, a friend from graduate school with whom he had become so close that he walked her down the aisle at her wedding. She served as his spokeswoman after his wife’s disappearance, and investigators have long suspected that she knew his secrets.

The police had always known Mr. Durst was in California when Ms. Berman was killed, but could not place him in Los Angeles. They suspected he was the author of a short anonymous note sent to the Beverly Hills police on the same day Ms. Berman was found shot in the head, saying there was a “cadaver” in her home. But a handwriting analysis performed in 2003 was inconclusive.

Photo

Mr. Durst after he was arrested on Saturday. Credit Orleans Parish Sheriff\'s Office
The makers of “The Jinx” obtained a letter written by Mr. Durst to Ms. Berman in which the lettering of the address on the envelope appears identical to that of the “cadaver” note, down to the misspelling of Beverly Hills as “Beverley.”

In the final episode, a forensic document examiner the filmmakers asked to analyze Mr. Durst’s handwriting concluded that the tics in the note’s handwriting “are unique to one person and only one person.”

Mr. Jarecki, who was also the show’s director, and Mr. Smerling struggled with whether to bring the letter to law enforcement authorities. If they did so too soon, their lawyers told them, they could be considered law enforcement agents in the event of a prosecution, possibly jeopardizing the material’s admissibility in court, Mr. Jarecki said.

They also wanted to preserve a journalistic privilege not to disclose sources or testify in court. Still, Mr. Smerling said in an interview, “We had a moral obligation and an obligation to the families of the dead to see that justice was done.” They began speaking to Los Angeles investigators in early 2013.

Near the documentary’s end, the filmmakers were packing up their equipment when Mr. Durst asked to use the bathroom. He did not remove his wireless microphone as he closed the door, however, and began to whisper to himself.

More than two years passed after the interview before the filmmakers found the audio.

Mr. Durst’s private monologue makes for good television. But it is unclear whether the recording of his comments could be used in court, some legal experts said, since they were made in a bathroom when he was alone and had an expectation of privacy.

“That’s pretty damning stuff,” said Daniel J. Castleman, the former chief of investigations in the Manhattan district attorney’s office. “The question is: Is it admissible in court?”

But Daniel C. Richman, a former federal prosecutor who is a professor at Columbia University Law School, said the statements could be admitted in court “so long as it can be shown that the tape wasn’t tampered with.”

John Lewin, the lead prosecutor in the investigation into Ms. Berman’s death, declined to comment on Sunday. Mr. Lewin has built a reputation for winning convictions in cold cases, some of them decades old.

Now he faces an opponent who has, time and again, slipped out of law enforcement’s grasp.</string>

    <string name="sample_text_ko">우울증, 변비, 영양소 부족…

살이 찌는 것은 당사자의 잘못된 생활방식 때문이라고 생각하는 사람이 많다. 하지만 조지타운 대학교 메디컬 센터 정신의학과의 로버트 히데이야 교수는 “실상 비만은 우리가 통제하기 어려운 요인들에 대한 신체의 반응일 수 있다”고 말한다.

그는 “비만은 본인의 책임이 아니라 의사의 도움을 받아야 개선될 수 있는 상황인 경우가 있다”면서 “호르몬 불균형에서 비타민 결핍, 처방약의 부작용 등 많은 요인이 체중 증가에 작용한다”고 말했다. 미국의 폭스뉴스가 체중이 늘어나는 뜻밖의 이유 5가지와 그 대책을 소개했다.

◆우울증이 있다=많은 항우울제가 체중 증가를 유발한다. 만일 당신이 우울하고 그 때문에 약을 복용하고 있다면 2.3kg~6.8kg이 늘어날 것으로 각오해야 한다. 히데이야 교수는 “몇 년에 걸쳐 차츰차츰 이정도 불어난다”고 말한다. 약을 먹지 않는다 해도 우울증 환자는 체중이 늘게 마련이라는 증거가 있다.

2010년 미국 공중보건저널에 발표된 논문에 따르면 슬프고 외로운 사람들은 그렇지 않은 사람보다 체중이 빨리 증가한다. 앨라배마 대학교의 벨린다 니덤 교수는 “이런 사람들은 고지방, 고칼로리의, 마음을 편하게 만들어주는 전통음식을 더 많이 먹고 있을 가능성이 있다”고 말한다. 그는 “혹은 육체적 활동을 덜하고 있을 가능성도 있다”고 덧붙였다.

노마린다 의과대학원의 도미니크 프라댕리드 교수는 “항우울제 탓에 체중이 늘어나고 있는 것으로 보이는 환자가 내게 오면 그 약을 서서히 끊으라고 말할 가능성이 있다”고 말한다. 그는 “나라면 기존 약을 끊고 체중을 줄이는 데 도움이 되는 웰뷰트린을 먹으라고 권할 가능성이 크다”고 덧붙였다. 만일 체중증가가 약 때문이 아니라면 운동을 권하고 부추기는 조언자나 동호인 지원 그룹을 찾아보는 것이 좋다.

◆잘못된 처방약을 먹고 있다=체중 증가를 유발하는 약은 많고도 많다. 피임약, 호르몬 요법제, 스테로이드, 심장병과 고혈압에 먹는 베타차단제, 타목시펜 같은 유방암 약, 일부 류머티스성 관절염약, 일부 편두통 및 역류성 식도염약 등이 그런 예다.

로체스타 대학교의 스티븐 위틀린 교수는 “이런 약들은 식욕을 증진시키는가 하면 신진대사에도 영향을 미친다”고 말했다. 약 때문에 체중이 느는 것이라고 의심한다면 의사가 그런 부작용이 없는 다른 약을 찾아줄 수 있다.

◆소화가 느리다=변비를 포함한 소화 문제도 체중 증가의 원인이 될 수 있다. 히데이야 교수는 “이상적으로는, 음식을 먹고 난 지 한 시간 남짓 지나면 변을 보아야 한다”면서 “하지만 하루 한 두 차례 변을 보는 것까지는 건강한 범주에 속한다”고 말했다. 변을 규칙적으로 보지 못한다면 탈수, 약물, 섬유질 섭취 부족, 혹은 장내 박테리아의 생태계 이상 등이 원인일 수 있다.

변비가 유일한 증상이라면 건강에 유익한 유산균이 들어있는 프로바이오틱스(생균제)를 먹으면 소화관이 제대로 작동하게 만들 수 있다. 섬유질이 많은 음식을 먹고 물을 충분히 마시는 것이 핵심이다. 메타무실 같은 식이섬유 보충제를 물에 타 먹는 것도 방법일 수 있다. 히데이야 교수는 “이런 제제는 장내 폐기물 뿐 아니라 지방 미립자를 흡수할 수도 있다”고 말했다. 그래도 해결되지 않으면 의사의 진단이 필요하다.

◆특정 영양소가 부족하다=비타민D, 마그네슘, 철분 등이 부족하면 면역계가 손상된다. 또한 신체 에너지 수준이 떨어지고 신진대사 방식이 바뀐다. 그러면 건강한 생활양식을 선택하기 어려워진다. 히데이야 교수는 “이런 사람은 에너지 부족을 보충하기 위해 카페인, 단 것, 단당류를 섭취할 가능성이 커진다” 면서 “달리기나 운동을 하기에는 체력이 부족하다는 느낌을 갖게 될 수도 있다”고 말한다.

대책으로는 붉은 살코기나 시금치를 먹어 철분 수준을 높이고 브라질 넛이나 아몬드를 통해 마그네슘 섭취를 늘리는 것이다. 다만 비타민D가 부족한 증상은 우유를 많이 먹거나 햇빛을 많이 쬐는 것으로는 회복이 거의 불가능하다.

히데이야 교수는 “비타민D 보충제를 먹어야 하는데 복용량이 과다하면 콩팥 결석의 위험이 있”면서 “적정량을 가늠하려면 시간이 걸린다”고 말했다. 그는 “3개월마다 혈액검사를 받아야 의사가 적정량을 알아내서 처방해줄 수 있다”고 말한다.

철분 보충제를 먹는 데도 약간의 주의가 필요하다. 갑상선 기능 부전증을 비롯해 인슐린 저항성을 유발할 위험이 있는 질병이 없는지를 의사가 먼저 체크해야 한다. 이것이 체중 증가의 원인일 수 있기 때문이다. 그런 뒤에 적절한 철분 보충제 섭취량을 의사가 정해줄 수 있다.

◆늙어가는 중이다=이는 필연적인 현상이다. 프라댕리드 교수는 “우리는 40, 50대가 되면 20대 때만큼 칼로리를 연소하지 못한다”면서 “따라서 음식을 적게 먹고 운동을 더 많이 해야 한다”고 말했다. 이어 “체중을 장기적으로 유지하는 데는 다이어트보다 운동이 더 중요하다는 연구 결과가 있다”고 덧붙였다.

프라댕리드 교수는 “살코기, 치즈, 콩 등 지방함량이 적은 단백질 식품을 먹으면 칼로리를 더 효과적으로 태울 수 있다”면서 “이에 비해 신체는 탄수화물을 더 늦게 연소하며 이를 저장하려는 경향이 있다”고 말했다. 지방이 적은 단백질을 먹고 탄수화물을 적게 먹는 것은 체중 증가를 막는 좋은 방법이다.

권순일 기자 (kstt77@kormedi.com)

[코메디닷컴][건강선물닷컴][코메디뉴스][이성주의 건강편지]

저작권ⓒ \'건강을 위한 정직한 지식\' 코메디닷컴 / 무단전재-재배포 금지</string>
</resources>
